A Guide to the John Reynoldson Butterworth Collection of Dinwiddie County Records, 1810-1894
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
John Reynoldson Butterworth Collection of Dinwiddie County Records, 1810-1894
The Library of Virginia
21625
11 leaves and 10 pages
John Reynoldson Butterworth
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from John R. Butterworth, DeWitt, Virginia, 4 October 1939
Biographical Information
John Reynoldson Butterworth was born 13 April 1903 in Dinwiddie County, Virginia, to Abner Goode Butterworth (1876-1950) and Julia Harris Butterworth (1880-1976). Butterworth collected several documents relating to Dinwiddie County's history. He died 26 August 1987 in Petersburg, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Dinwiddie County records, 1810-1894, collected by John Reynoldson Butterworth (1903-1987) of Dinwiddie County, Virginia, consisting of accounts, including one with the Commonwealth of Virginia; correspondence to Isaac Roney (1800-1870) of Dinwiddie County concerning personal and business matters; deeds for property in Dinwiddie County and for a release from claims; judicial records, including a declaration and answers, a decree, a judgment, and writs, from Dinwiddie County; and promissory notes to Isaac Roney as administrator of Rebecca Roney, including miscellaneous notes.
Contents List
- Deed, 31 May 1810 and recorded in Dinwiddie County, Virginia, 21 January 1811, for 402 1/2 acres in Dinwiddie County from Baker Pegram (1758-1830) and Mary Pegram to Thomas Field (d. ca. 1832), all of Dinwiddie County.
- Account, dated 28 July 1817 and settled 1 September 1820, of Thomas Travis with John L. Scott (ca. 1795-1835) of Dinwiddie County.
- Promissory notes, 1823, to Isaac Roney (1800-1870), administrator of Rebecca Roney (d. ca. 1823), both of Dinwiddie County.
- Deed of release, 7 May 1825, from John D. Townes (1790-1839) of Petersburg, Virginia, to John L. Scott.
- Letter, 20 August 1839, from Thomas Y. Jobb of Amelia County, Virginia, to Isaac Roney.
- Writ, 14 September 1839, issued by Isaac Roney as Justice of the Peace in relation to Mark Andrews (b. ca. 1797) of Dinwiddie County.
- Letter from Jones Blount and Company to Isaac Roney.
- Account, dated January-October 1857 and settled 16 November 1859, of Isaac Roney with Benjamin R. Lewis (ca. 1819-1866) and John Peter Goodwyn (1826-1895).
- Declaration, 16 January 1871, of Benjamin P. King (1801-1875) and Martha Dyson (b. ca. 1797) against George J. Brown (b. ca. 1808), administrator of John B. Dyson (d. ca. 1870) and the answers, dated 16 January 1871, of Brown and William Ettenborough (1825-1890), all of Dinwiddie County.
- Decree in suit of King and Dyson vs. Brown.
- Writ, November 1885, and a judgment, dated 27 November 1885, issued by James Holt Boisseau (d. 1919), Justice of the Peace, in relation to J. H. (b. ca. 1843) and Carter E. Hogwood (b. ca. 1840).
- Account, dated July 1894 and certified August 1894, of monies owed by the Commonwealth of Virginia to William Benjamin Procise (1853-1917).